Previously on the show.
Episode sebelumnya.
Weslie drove Magic Train into the waterspout,
Weslie mengendarai Kereta Ajaib ke waterspout,
allowing Wolffy to recombine with his duplicates.
memungkinkan Wolffy reuni dengan duplikatnya.
But the evil Black Cloud appeared,
Tapi Awan Hitam yang jahat muncul,
disguised as a poor little fish,
menyamar sebagai ikan kecil,
attacking everyone and stealing the sky crystal.
menyerang semua orang dan mencuri kristal langit.
Can the goats get it back?
Bisakah kambing mendapatkannya kembali?
"Flying Island: The Sky Adventure: The Final Battle"
Petualangan Langit Pulau Terbang: Pertarungan Terakhir.
I just need to throw the sky crystal into the volcano.
Tinggal lempar kristal langit ke gunung berapi.
Give the sky crystal back to us now!
Kembalikan kristal langit sekarang!
You want to stop me from destroying it?
Mau mencegahku menghancurkannya?
Try getting through these water columns!
Coba lewati kolom air ini!
We won't let you succeed!
Takkan kami biarkan kau lolos!
What was that?
Apa itu?
Oh, no, the whole tunnel is moving!
Gawat, seluruh terowongan bergerak!
Wow! That's a huge waterspout!
Itu waterspout yang besar!
How did this happen?
Bagaimana ini bisa terjadi?
Black Cloud must have used the crystal to attract the waterspout towards him.
Awan Hitam pasti memakai kristal untuk menarik waterspout mendekatinya.
-We're almost home!
Kita hampir sampai rumah!
But we lost the sky crystal and the goats.
Tapi kita kehilangan kristal langit dan kambing.
The crystal and the goats!
Kristal dan kambing!
What was that?
Apa itu?
Why do we keep running into them?
Kenapa kita terus bertemu mereka?
A waterspout!
Waterspout!
We've been cornered!
Kita sudah terpojok!
What should we do?
Kita harus bagaimana?
Master!
Master!
Thank you for saving us!
Terima kasih sudah membantu!
Oh, no! Black Cloud has gotten away!
Gawat! Awan Hitam berhasil lolos!
He's not going anywhere!
Dia takkan bisa lolos!
It's Cloud Giant!
Raksasa Awan!
Hand the sky crystal over.
Berikan kristal langit.
In your dreams!
Teruslah bermimpi!
Don't hit me!
Jangan pukul aku!
I'm innocent!
Aku tak bersalah!
Wolffy, are you okay?
Wolffy, kau tak apa-apa?
Black Cloud! Stop!
Awan Hitam! Hentikan!
Quick, let's go after him.
Cepat, mari kejar dia.
Go and teach him a lesson now!
Pergi dan beri dia pelajaran!
Black Cloud! You'll pay for this!
Awan Hitam! Kau akan membayarnya!
The sunshine is so nice. It's the best time to get a tan.
Sinar mataharinya terik. Ideal untuk berjemur.
It was great just now. How come it's suddenly so dark?
Barusan keadaan cerah. Kenapa tiba-tiba gelap?
Is this a dream?
Apa ini mimpi?
Run, everybody!
Lari, Semuanya!
Are you all right, bunny?
Kau baik-baik saja?
Stop right there!
Berhenti!
Who... are you exactly?
Siapa kau sebenarnya?
You don't remember me anymore?
Kau sungguh tak ingat aku?
Then I must destroy sky crystal.
Maka kristal langit harus hancur.
Let me out of here! You can't destroy the sky crystal!
Keluarkan aku! Kau tak bisa menghancurkan kristal langit!
Just stay here until I've destroyed it.
Tetap di sini sampai aku menghancurkannya.
Black Cloud!
Awan Hitam!
Cloud Giant?
Raksasa Awan?
How come you're trapped in there? I'll get you out.
Kenapa kau terjebak di sana? Aku akan mengeluarkanmu.
Don't bother trying.
Itu tak perlu.
Without sky crystal, I can't get out.
Tanpa kristal langit, aku tak bisa keluar.
Go after Black Cloud. Don't let him destroy sky crystal!
Kejar Awan Hitam. Jangan sampai kristal langit!
I have a plan. But I'll need Wolffy's help.
Aku punya rencana, tapi aku butuh bantuan Wolffy.
Me?
Aku?
Stop, Black Cloud!
Berhenti, Awan Hitam!
Nobody can stop me from destroying the sky crystal.
Aku harus bisa menghancurkan kristal langit.
So annoying! What's the point of flying around me?
Menyebalkan sekali! Apa gunanya terbang di sekelilingku?
You never know.
Itu kejutan.
I can't move?
Aku jadi kaku?
Hand over the sky crystal!
Serahkan kristal langit!
You don't understand.
Kau tak mengerti.
I have to destroy sky crystal!
Aku harus menghancurkan kristal langit!
How come he's still moving?
Kenapa dia masih bergerak?
We can't hold him back any longer.
Dia hampir bebas!
Life will go back to what it used to be.
Hidup akan kembali seperti semula.
Stop!
Berhenti!
Here I am!
Aku di sini!
You're finally here, Wolffy!
Akhirnya kau di sini, Wolffy!
The main character always shows up at the end.
Karakter utama selalu muncul di akhir.
I summon you!
Aku memanggilmu!
Stop it, Black Cloud!
Hentikan, Awan Hitam!
Don't take the sky crystal away!
Jangan ambil kristal langit!
I need to destroy it.
Aku harus menghancurkannya.
Give it back.
Kembalikan.
Give it back! I must destroy it!
Kembalikan! Harus kuhancurkan.
Great, the sky crystal is safe.
Bagus, kristal langit aman.
Our plan worked!
Rencana kita berhasil.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
We can't let Black Cloud off the hook.
Jangan abaikan Awan Hitam.
I'm going to teach you a lesson!
Aku akan memberimu pelajaran!
I didn't do anything wrong!
Aku tak bersalah!
Cloud Giant, teach him a lesson.
Cloud Giant, beri dia pelajaran.
Wolffy, calm down.
Wolffy, tenanglah.
He's an old friend of mine.
Dia adalah teman lamaku.
You finally remember me.
Akhirnya kau ingat juga.
Your name is Dicky. You were the first double I made.
Namamu Dicky. Kau tiruan pertama yang kubuat.
We used to play together.
Dulu kami bermain bersama.
But then you disappeared all of a sudden.
Lalu kau mendadak menghilang.
You left so you could do bad things, did you?
Kau pergi demi hal buruk, bukan?
It was because...
Itu karena...
Cloud Giant, we haven't played together for so long.
Raksasa Awan,, kita sudah lama tak main.
I've been busy lately. We'll play another time.
Belakangan aku sibuk. Kita akan bermain lain kali.
Ever since you started managing the Cloud Sea tunnel,
Sejak kau mulai menjaga terowongan Lautan Awan,
you stopped playing with me.
kau berhenti bermain denganku.
Was that why you took the sky crystal?
Makanya kau ambil kristal langit?
-So that the waterspout would vanish? -Yes.
- Agar waterspout itu menghilang? - Ya.
Still, you shouldn't have taken the crystal.
Tetap saja, kau seharusnya tak mengambil kristal itu.
You've hurt many people
Kau menyakiti banyak orang
and destroyed their homes.
dan menghancurkan rumah mereka.
I'm sorry!
Maafkan aku!
Then you'll have to make it up to them. Understood?
Maka kau harus menebusnya. Mengerti?
Yes.
Ya.
I don't understand. Dicky was a different color in your memories.
Aku tak mengerti. Dicky punya warna berbeda di ingatanmu.
That's because...
Itu karena...
I'll draw something for Cloud Giant.
Aku akan menggambar untuk Raksasa Awan.
I look so imperfect now. That's not okay!
Aku tampak sangat tak sempurna sekarang. Ini buruk!
Perfect!
Sempurna!
Are you really not coming back with us?
Kau tak mau kembali bersama kami?
My journey with Auntie Bowie and the others isn't over yet.
Ada perjalananku bersama Bibi Bowie dan yang lain.
Chief, we're all set!
Pak Kepala, kita sudah siap!
Take care then.
Jaga dirimu.
You too.
Kau juga.
-We have such a crowd today. -Yes!
- Ada banyak orang hari ini. - Ya!
THE END
TAMAT